Guide to the New-York Historical Society Geographic Images Collection circa 1600-2006 PR 20
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: New York City Views - Manhattan
  - Subseries IA: MANHATTAN - BOXED MATERIAL
    - Manhattan - Boxed Material - Buildings
      - Buildings-Theaters-M-N miscellaneous (Box 84, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Madison Square Garden (Box 84, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Metropolitan Opera House (Box 84, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Henry Miller's Theater, 126 W. 43rd Street (Box 84, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Niblo's Garden (Box 84, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Theaters-O-P miscellaneous (Box 84, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Olympic (Box 85, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Park Theatre (Box 85, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Q-R miscellaneous (Box 85, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Theaters-S-T miscellaneous (Box 85, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Theaters-U-V miscellaneous (Box 85, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Theaters-W-Z miscellaneous (Box 85, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Unidentified (Box 85, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Transportation Stations-Barge Office-Battery Park (Box 85, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Transportation Stations-Ferry Terminal- General (Box 85, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Transportation Stations-Ferry Terminal-Fulton Ferry (Box 85, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Transportation Stations-Ferry Terminal- Hoboken Ferry terminal (Box 85, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Transportation Stations- Railroad Terminals-Grand Central Station (Box 86, Folder 1-4)
      - Buildings-Transportation Stations- Railroad Terminals-Pennsylvania Station (Box 86, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Transportation Stations- Railroad Terminals-Elevated Railroads General (Box 86, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Transportation Stations- Railroad Terminals-Elevated Railroad, South Ferry Terminal of 6th/9th Ave. lines (Box 86, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Transportation Stations- Misc. (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - Manhattan - Boxed Material - Transportation
      - Transportation-Boats and Ferries (Box 87, Folder 1)
      - Transportation-Horse-drawn vehicles (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - Transportation-Railroads-Elevated Railroads-Construction (Box 87, Folder 3)
      - Transportation-Railroads-Elevated Railroads: Locomotives (Box 87, Folder 4-5)
      - Transportation-Railroads-Elevated Railroads-Cars (Box 87, Folder 6)
      - Transportation-Railroads-Elevated Railroads-Stations, Platforms and Kiosks (Box 87, Folder 7)
      - Transportation-Railroads-Elevated Railroads-Gilbert Elevated Railroads (Box 88, Folder 1)
      - Transportation-Railroads-Elevated Railroads-Second and Third Avenue El (Box 88, Folder 2)
      - Transportation-Railroads-Elevated Railroads-Third Avenue El (Box 88, Folder 3)
      - Transportation-Railroads-Elevated Railroads-Sixth Avenue El (to 59th street) (Box 88, Folder 4)
      - Transportation-Railroads-Elevated Railroads-Ninth Avenue El (above 59th street) (Box 88, Folder 5-6)
      - Transportation-Railroads-Elevated Railroads-Ninth Avenue El (110th street curve) (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - Transportation-Railroads-Elevated Railroads-Sixth and Ninth Avenue El (Terminal Yard at 155th-159th street) (Box 89, Folder 2)
      - Transportation-Railroads-Horse-drawn Railroads (Box 89, Folder 3)
      - Transportation-Railroads-Street Railroads (Box 89, Folder 4-5)
      - Transportation-Railroads-Street Railroads (Box 90, Folder 1)
      - Transportation-Railroads-Stages (Box 90, Folder 2)
      - Transportation-Subway-Beach Pneumatic Tubes (Box 90, Folder 3)
      - Transportation-Subway-Construction (Box 90, Folder 4)
      - Transportation-Subway-Ground-breakings and Opening ceremonies (IRT, BMT) (Box 90, Folder 5)
      - Transportation-Subway-Station Interiors and Exteriors (Box 90, Folder 6)
      - Transportation-Subway-BMT (Box 90, Folder 7)
      - Transportation-Subway-IRT (Box 90, Folder 8)
      - Transportation-Subway-Renovations of Wall St. and Columbus Circle (2008) (Box 90, Folder 9)
      - Transportation-Tunnels-Manhattan and Hudson (under Hudson - possibly for PATH trains) (Box 91, Folder 1)
      - Transportation-Tunnels-Holland Tunnel (Box 91, Folder 2-3)
      - Transportation-Tunnels-Lincoln Tunnel (Box 91, Folder 4)
      - Transportation-Tunnels-NYC Tunnels by Ole Singstad (Brooklyn Battery Tunnel and others) (Box 91, Folder 5)
      - Transportation-Miscellaneous (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Manhattan - Boxed Material - Utilities
      - Utilities-Croton Aqueduct and Reservoir (Box 91, Folder 7)
      - Utilities-Sewer/Subway Construction (Box 91, Folder 8)
      - Utilities-Manhole Covers, photographed by Hertha Bauer (ca. 1980-1983) (Box 91, Folder 9)
      - Utilities-General (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Manhattan - Boxed Material - Events
      - Events-Antique Shows-Rockefeller Center, 1934 (Box 92, Folder 1)
      - Events-Blizzard of 1888 (Box 92, Folder 2-5)
      - Events-Blizzard of Dec. 27, 1947 (Box 93, Folder 1-3)
      - Events-Celebrations-Erie Canal Celebration (1825) (Box 93, Folder 4)
      - Events-Celebrations-Croton Water Celebration (1842) (Box 93, Folder 5)
      - Events-Celebrations-Atlantic Cable Celebration (1858) (Box 93, Folder 6)
      - Events-Celebrations-Washington Inaugural Centennial Celebration (1889) (Box 94, Folder 1-4)
      - Events-Celebrations-Washington Inaugural Centennial Celebration (1889) (Box 95, Folder 1-2)
      - Events-Celebrations-Columbian Quadricentennial Celebration, 1892 (Box 95, Folder 3)
      - Events-Celebrations-Harlem Ship Canal Opening, 1895 (Box 95, Folder 4)
      - Events-Celebrations-Hudson-Fulton Celebration, 1909 (Box 96, Folder 1-6)
      - Events-Exhibits-Exhibit of American and Foreign Uniforms, 1911 (Box 97, Folder 1)
      - Events-Exhibits-The Gates, Central Park, 2005 (Box 97, Folder 2)
      - Events-Exhibits-Miscellaneous (Box 97, Folder 3)
      - Events-Fairs-Crystal Palace International Exposition, 1853 (Box 97, Folder 4-5)
      - Events-Fairs-Metropolitan Fair, 1863 (Box 97, Folder 6)
      - Events-Fairs-American Institute Fair, 1888 (Box 97, Folder 7)
      - Events-Fairs-Street Fairs (East 92nd Street, 1970) (Box 97, Folder 8)
      - Events-Fairs-Miscellaneous (Box 97, Folder 9)
      - Events-Fires-Burning of Barnum's Museum, 1865 (Box 97, Folder 10)
      - Events-Fires-Miscellaneous (Box 97, Folder 11)
      - Events-Funerals-Andrew Jackson funerary parade, 1845 (Box 98, Folder 1)
      - Events-Funerals-U.S. Grant funeral procession, 1885 (Box 98, Folder 2)
      - Events-Funerals-Grant's Tomb Cornerstone Laying, 1892 (Box 98, Folder 3)
      - Events-Funerals-Lincoln's Funeral, and others (Box 98, Folder 4)
      - Events-Holidays-Memorial Day ceremonies (Box 98, Folder 5)
      - Events-Holidays-Miscellaneous (Box 98, Folder 6)
      - Events-Parades-Visit of the Prince of Wales Parade, 1860 (Box 98, Folder 7)
      - Events-Parades-Civil War parades (Box 98, Folder 8)
      - Events-Parades-Naval Parade (Homecoming of the Fleet), 1898 (Box 98, Folder 9)
      - Events-Parades-Dewey Naval Parade, September 29, 1899 (Box 98, Folder 10)
      - Events-Parades-Dewey Land Parade, September 30, 1899 (Box 99, Folder 1)
      - Events-Parades- World War I parades, 1918 (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - Events-Parades-Victory and other World War I parades, 1919 (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - Events-Parades-Charles Lindbergh parade, 1927 (Box 99, Folder 4-5)
      - Events-Parades-WPA parade, 1937 (Box 99, Folder 6)
      - Events-Parades-May Day parade, 1937 (Box 99, Folder 7)
      - Events-Parades-American League Against War and fascism parade, 1937 (Box 99, Folder 8)
      - Events-Parades-Stop Hitler parade, March 25, 1939 (Box 99, Folder 9)
      - Events-Parades-Robert Burns parade, ca. 1950 (Box 99, Folder 10)
      - Events-Parades-Parade welcoming General McArthur to New York, 1951 (Box 99, Folder 11)
      - Events-Parades-Western Hemisphere Day Parade, 1960 (Box 99, Folder 12)
      - Events-Parades-Easter parades (Box 99, Folder 13)
      - Events-Parades-St. Patrick's Day parades (Box 99, Folder 14)
      - Events-Parades-Macy's Thanksgiving Day parades (Box 99, Folder 15)
      - Events-Parades-Police parades (Box 99, Folder 16)
      - Events-Parades-Miscellaneous (Box 99, Folder 17)
      - Events-Political Campaigns-1844 Presidential Campaign (Box 100, Folder 1)
      - Events-Political Campaigns-1856 Presidential Campaign (Box 100, Folder 2)
      - Events-Political Campaigns-1872 Presidential Campaign and Election (Box 100, Folder 3)
      - Events-Political Campaigns-1924 Democratic Convention at Madison Square Garden (Box 100, Folder 4)
      - Events-Political Campaigns-1936 Election Charter Revision and Presidential Campaign (Box 100, Folder 5)
      - Events-Political Campaigns-1940 Presidential Campaign and Election (Box 100, Folder 6)
      - Events-Political Demonstrations-Miscellaneous political demonstrations (Box 100, Folder 7)
      - Events-Riots-Astor Place Riot, 1849 (Box 100, Folder 8)
      - Events-Riots-Civil War Draft Riots, 1863 (Box 100, Folder 9)
      - Events-Shipwrecks-General Slocum Shipwreck and sinking, 1904 (Box 100, Folder 10-11)
      - Events-Sports Events (Box 100, Folder 12)
      - Events-Wall Street Bombing, 1920 (Box 100, Folder 13)
      - Events-Miscellaneous (Box 100, Folder 14)
  - Subseries IB: MANHATTAN - FLAT MATERIALS - PRINTS
    - Manhattan - Flat Material - Prints - Views
      - REMOVED to PR 353 Birdseye Views- Bachman, J., 1849, 1861, 1865, ca. 1888 (Folder FF1)
        Separated Materials
        These prints, as well as others in this collection by John Bachmann, have been removed and placed in PR 353 Collection of John Bachmann Prints.
      - Birdseye Views- Currier and Ives, 1856, 1875, 1876 (Folder FF2)
      - Birdseye Views- Harnisch, engraver, 1869 (Folder FF3)
      - Birdseye Views- Magnus, Charles, 1865, 1877 (Folder FF4)
      - Birdseye Views- Later reproductions of 18th c. Views of Dutch New Amsterdam (Folder FF5)
      - Birdseye Views- Views from the 1850s, 1850-1853 (Folder FF6)
        Scope and Contents Note
        New-York, A. Gocht, after H. Trommer (German)
        New-York et Brooklyn/Nueva York y Brooklyn, Th. Muller after Simpson 1850
        Souvenir of New York, J. Bornet 1851
        The City of New York from [ ] Hill, New Jersey, J. Bornet, published by David McLellan 1853.
      - Birdseye Views- Views from the 1860s, 1867-1868 (Folder FF7)
        New-York, Ch. Rost, published by Th. Schrickel
        New York and Environs, R. Kupfer, engraver, printed by Peters, 1867.
        New York and Environs/und Umgebung, Deutz Brothers, lith., published by George Degen, 1868.
      - Birdseye Views- Views from the 1870s, 1874-1879 (Folder FF8)
        New York, taken from Central Park, G. Schlegel, lith., published by George Degen, 1874.
        New York, Published by Rogers, Peet & Co., 1879
      - Birdseye Views- Views from the 20th century, 1903-1911 (Folder FF9)
      - Birdseye Views- Views from the Singer Building, 1911 (Folder FF10)
      - Harbor Views- 17th Century (Folder FF11)
        N. Amsterdam, ou N. Iork, Peter Mortier, 1700
        Nieu Amsterdam [shows 1673], Peter Schenk/Amfield, 1702.
      - Harbor Views- 19th Century reproductions of 17th Century Views (Folder FF12)
      - Harbor Views- 20th Century reproductions of 17th century views (Folder FF13)
      - Harbor Views- 18th Century (Folder FF14)
        The South Prospect of the City of New York in America, engraved for the London Magazine, 1761
      - Harbor Views- Facsimiles of the Burgis and Bakewell views (Folder FF15)
      - Harbor Views- 19th Century reproductions of 18th century views (Folder FF16)
        including facsimiles of St. Memin's "A View of the City of New York from Brooklyn Heights, 1789"
      - Harbor Views- Views of the City of New York in 1792 (Folder FF17)
        Hayward's Lithography for Valentine's Manual, 1850
      - Harbor Views- New York about 1790 (Folder FF18)
        Hayward's Lithography for Valentine's Manual, 1862
      - Harbor Views- 20th Century reproductions of 18th Century views (Folder FF19)
      - Harbor Views- 1800 - 1839 (Folder FF20)
        A Schooner with a View of New York, Clark & Hamble, engr., Edw'd Orme, London, pub. 1807
        New York Bay from Staten Island, Henry J. Beckwith, engr., Putnam, pub.
        New-York from Weehawk, A.J. Davis, lithographer, 1830
        New York from Brooklyn Heights, Graham after Wharton, pub. In New York Mirror, 1830
        View of the Bay and Harbour of New York, from the Battery, Smith after Burton, pub. in New York Mirror, 1830
        Entry to the Bay of New-York, Salathe after Ch. Bodmar, 1839
        New-York taken from Fort Columbus, Governor's Island 1816, Hayward's Lithography for Valentine's Manual ,1860.
      - Harbor Views- 1840 - 1849 (Folder FF21)
      - Harbor Views- Views by Havell, 1844. Panoramic View of New York taken from the North River; Panoramic View of New York taken from the East River. Robert Havell (Folder FF22)
        Panoramic View of New York taken from the North River, 1844, Robert Havell
        Panoramic View of New York taken from the East River, 1844, Robert Havell.
      - Harbor Views- 1846-1848 (Folder FF23)
        New York taken from the Northwest Angle of Fort Columbus, Governor's Island, 1846, Henry Papprill, after Catherwood
        New York and Environs from Williamsburgh, 1848, E.W. Foreman and E. Brown Jr.
      - Harbor Views- Views by Nathaniel Currier, 1849 (Folder FF24)
        City of New York, from Jersey City, Nathaniel Currier, lithographer, 1849
        New York Bay from the Telegraph Station, Nathaniel Currier, lithographer, 1849
        View of New York from Brooklyn Heights, Nathaniel Currier, lithographer, 1849
        View of New York from Weehawken-North River, Nathaniel Currier, lithographer, 1849.
      - Harbor Views- 1850 - 1859 (Folder FF25)
        New-York, Vue Prise du Fort de William-Castle, Lebreton, lithographer, printed in Paris [1850-59]
        Vue de New-York, Prise de L'Ile Ellis, Lebreton, lithographer, printed in Paris [1850-59].
      - Harbor Views- 1850-1851 (Folder FF26)
        View of New York and its Environs taken from the Heights of West Hoboken, Jacottet and Bayot, lithographers, [1850]
        View of New York from the East River, Robert Hinshel, engraver (attributed), 1851
        Souvenir of New York, C. Gildemeister, lithographer after J. Bornet, 1851
        View of New York from the North River.
      - Harbor Views- Floating Grain Elevators (Folder FF27)
      - Harbor Views- 1860 - 1899 (Folder FF28)
        New York Bay, from Bay Ridge, L.I., Currier & Ives, 1860
        The Harbour of New York from the Brooklyn Bridge Tower Looking South-west, Currier & Ives.
      - Harbor Views- 1900 and later (Folder FF29)
      - Winter Views (Folder FF30)
        Sleighing in New York, Benecke, lithographer
        Life in New York! (Sleighing in Winter), J. Dorival, publisher.
      - Fictitious Views, French/German (Folder FF31)
        Nowel Amsterdam en L'Amerique 1672 (Quebec origin)
        [View in 1666]
        [Triumphal Entry of Royal Troops to New York]
        [Debarkment of English troops at New York]
        Related Archival Materials Note
        See also: similar views filed under Boston and Philadelphia
      - Fictitious Views, French/German origin (Folder FF32)
        [Destruction of the Royal Statue in New York] (4)
        [Terrible Fire in New York September 19, 1776] (2)
        [The Arrival of Prince William Henry October 16 1781]
        Incendie de New-Yorck, 1835 [Great Fire of 1835]
      - General views/Sets of views (Folder FF33)
        "The Picturesque Tourist" 1845
        "The Pocket Annual" 1848
        "Historical New York," Albertypes from the Leonard
        Hassam Bogart Collection, 1939
        "An Album of Contemporary New York" [1950-70]
    - Manhattan - Flat Material - Prints - Rivers
      - East River (General) (Folder FF34)
      - East River (Hell Gate) (Folder FF35)
      - Harlem River (Folder FF36)
    - Manhattan - Flat Material - Prints - Islands
      - Liberty Island (Bedloe's Island)and Statue of Liberty (Folder FF37)
      - Islands, other (Folder FF38)
        Governor's Island
        Randall's Island
        Roosevelt Island (Welfare Island/Blackwell's Island)
        Ward's Island
    - Manhattan - Flat Material - Prints - Bridges
      - Brooklyn Bridge (Folder FF39)
      - High Bridge (Folder FF40)
      - Bridges, other (Folder FF41)
        Harlem Bridge
        Manhattan Bridge
        Williamsburg Bridge
    - Manhattan - Flat Material - Prints - Street Views
      - A - B named streets (Folder FF42)
        Albany Street; Baxter Street; Barclay Street; Beekman Street; Bowery
      - Broad Street (Folder FF43)
      - Broadway- Battery Place north to Wall Street (Folder FF44)
      - Broadway- Wall Street north to Fulton Street (Folder FF45)
      - Broadway- Fulton Street north to Worth Street (Folder FF46-47)
      - Broadway- looking south from Barclay Street and Park to American Museum, St. Paul's, Astor House (Folder FF48)
      - Broadway- View of St. Paul's and the Broadway Stages, 1831 (Folder FF49)
      - Broadway- Worth Street north to 23rd Street (Folder FF50)
      - C - L named streets (Folder FF51)
        Canal Street; Cherry Street; Coenties Slip; Dover Street; Edgar Street; Fulton Street; Herald Square; Hester Street; Liberty Street
      - M - P named streets (Folder FF52)
        Madison Avenue, Madison Square, Maiden Lane, Murray Street, Park Avenue, Park Place, Park Row, Pine Street, Printing House Square
      - Q - Z named streets (Folder FF53)
        South Street, West Street
      - Wall Street (Folder FF54-55)
      - Numbered Streets and Avenues (Folder FF56)
        42nd Street (Fifth Avenue to Lexington Avenue); W. 80th Street (Columbus Avenue to Amsterdam Avenue); Second Avenue (north from 42nd St.); Fifth Avenue (north and south from 42nd St.)
    - Manhattan - Flat Material - Prints - Neighborhoods
      - Five Points/Collect Pond (Folder FF57)
      - Chinatown,Greenwich Village, Harlem, Manhattanville (Folder FF58)
    - Manhattan - Flat Material - Prints - Parks and Gardens
      - Battery Park (Folder FF59-60)
      - Central Park (Genre prints published by Schile) (Folder FF61)
      - Central Park (Maps, plans, panoramas) (Folder FF62)
      - Central Park (Buildings, monuments, structures, etc.) (Folder FF63)
      - Central Park (Activities and events with winter sports) (Folder FF64)
      - City Hall Park (19th century) (Folder FF65)
      - City Hall Park (later repros of 19th century prints) (Folder FF66)
      - Jones Wood (Folder FF67)
      - Union Square (Folder FF68)
      - Gardens- Elgin Botanic Garden; Palace Garden (Folder FF69)
    - Manhattan - Flat Material - Prints - Buildings
      - Armories- Seventh Regiment (3rd Ave at 6th St.) (Folder FF70)
      - Baths- Russian Baths (Folder FF71)
      - Churches and Synagogues- Protestant Episcopal Churches after G. Stacy photographs; misc. pew plans, 1867 (Folder FF72)
      - Churches and Synagogues- A- E (Folder FF73)
        All Souls Unitarian Church
        Annunciation Episcopal Church (pew plan)
        Bethel Ship John Wesley
        B'nai Jeshurun
        Brick Presbyterian Church (includes pew plan)
        Calvary Episcopal Church
        Christ's Lutheran Church
        Divine Unity, Church of (pew plan)
      - Churches and Synagogues- F - I (Folder FF74)
        First Congregational Church
        First Presbyterian Church
        Floating Church of Our Savior
        Holy Communion, Church of the
        Incarnation, Episcopal Church of the (pew plan)
      - Churches and Synagogues- First Methodist Episcopal and First Mariners Methodist Episcopal Church (Folder FF75)
      - Churches and Synagogues- Grace Church (Folder FF76)
      - Churches and Synagogues- J - R (Folder FF77)
        Little Church Around the Corner (Church of the Transfiguration)
        Messiah, Unitarian Church of the (pew plan)
        Middle Dutch Church
        Moravian Church
        New Dutch Church
        North Reformed Dutch Church
        Puritans, Presbyterian Church of the
      - Churches and Synagogues- S - Z (Folder FF78)
        St. Alphonsus
        St. Ann's Church for Deaf Mutes
        St. Bernard's
        St. Esprit, Eglise Francoise du
        St. George's Episcopal Church
        St. Johannes
        St. John's Episcopal Chapel
        St. John the Divine, Episcopal Cathedral Church of
        St. Michael's
        St. Thomas Episcopal Church
        South Dutch Church
      - Churches and Synagogues- St. Mark's Episcopal in the Bouwerie (Folder FF79)
      - Churches and Synagogues- St. Patrick's Roman Catholic Cathedral (Folder FF80)
      - Churches and Synagogues- St. Paul's Episcopal Chapel (Folder FF81)
      - Churches and Synagogues- Trinity Church (Folder FF82)
        includes "Birdseye View of Trinity Church," 1847, by John Forsyth; and a drawing of old Trinity Church by A.J. Davis.
      - Clubs and Societies- Masonic Hall and Union League Club (Folder FF83)
      - Clubs and Societies- Tammany Hall (Folder FF84)
      - Financial and Commercial- Banks (Folder FF85)
      - Financial and Commercial- Merchant's Exchange (Folder FF86)
      - Financial and Commercial- Produce Exchange and Stock Exchange (Folder FF87)
      - Financial and Commercial- Insurance (Folder FF88)
        Equitable Life Building
        International Insurance Company Building
        Metropolitan Life Building
      - Financial and Commercial- Markets (Folder FF89)
        Fulton Fish Market
        Washington Market
      - Financial and Commercial- Offices (Folder FF90)
        130 Broadway
        Adams Building, 61 Broadway
        American Express Depot and Offices
        AT&T World Headquarters
        Flatiron Building
        Rockefeller Center
      - Financial and Commercial- Stores and Shops (Folder FF91)
        Atlantic Dynamite Company
        Bagoe's first drugstore
        Bourne's Stationers
        Devlin & Co., Clothiers & Gentlemen's Furnishings
        Allen Dodworth, music teacher
        Doremus, Suydams & Nixon Dry Goods
        M. & S.S. Howell, dealers in Gun Powder
        Phelps & Peck's (ruins of)
        T.J. Wood's Tool Store
        John W. Quincy, Cut Nails & Iron
      - Financial and Commercial- Stores and Shops (large) (Folder 91.5)
        A. T. Stewart's Dept. Store
        Knox the Hatter
        Siegel-Cooper Dept. Store
      - Government Buildings- Castle Garden Immigration Station (Folder FF92)
      - Government Buildings- City Hall, Wall Street (Folder FF93)
      - Government Buildings- City Hall (Holland/Robinson view) (Folder FF94)
      - Government Buildings- City Hall, in City Hall Park (Folder FF95)
      - Government Buildings- Custom House, Wall Street and Bowling Green (Folder FF96)
      - Government Buildings- Fire Departments and Fire Houses (Folder FF97)
      - Government Buildings- Government House, Bowling Green (Folder FF98)
      - Government Buildings- Post Offices (Folder FF99)
      - Government Buildings- Prisons (Folder FF100)
      - Government Buildings- other (Folder FF101)
        City Hall, Dutch (Stadt Huys), Pearl Street
        Municipal Building
        Hall of Records, City Hall Park
      - Hotels- A - E (Folder FF102)
        Albion Hotel
        American Hotel
        Hotel Astor
        Athenaeum Hotel
        Hotel Croton
      - Hotels- City Hotel (Folder FF103)
      - Hotels- F- M (Folder FF104)
        Fifth Avenue Hotel
        Gramercy Park Hotel
        Grand Union Hotel
        Hurlgate Ferry House
        Madison Cottage
        Metropolitan Hotel
      - Hotels- N - Z (Folder FF105)
        New York Hotel
        Park Hotel
        Savoy Plaza and Netherland